# MAJID NAZIR

4923367300092 Peshawar, Pakistan @ mkhan\_22@hotmail.com 🐓 https://github.com/confirmit1

### SUMMARY

A Seasoned Full-Stack Web Developer with 5+ years experience in the industry and a comprehensive educational background has allowed me to improve efficiency and profits through use of information systems, and am able to use my knowledge of business theory and methodology to create practical, measurable procedures and solutions for immediate implementation.

### **EXPERIENCE**

# Oxford Policy Management Sep 2019 - Jun 2020, Peshawar, Pakistan Research Associate

I was part of a DFID (Department for International Development, Now FCDO) UK government body's funded HEART consotium that is helping the Khyber Pakhtunkhwa's Health Department for the betterment of its service delivery. In light of this, our team has successfully assessed the Routine MISs of the directorate. The core duties assigned to me were as follows:

- Data collection using the PRISM tool prepared by USAID's MEASURE Evaluation Programme.
- Writing and Editing high-quality reports.
- Creating an online respository for storing and retrival of collected data.
- Sharing data and reports with the team.
- Supporting the Operations Staff in the usage of in-house IT equipment.

# Malik Khan Cargo Service Jul 2017 - Sep 2019, Peshawar, Pakistan Full Stack Developer

The Organization is a logistics company that provides service to clients in Afghanistan and Pakistan.

- I was responsible for coding, deploying and maintainance of an internal web application using the MERN Stack.
- The Front-end consisted of a dashboard that had a functionality of producing auto-generated reports including graphs. The graphs were incorporated using react-chart-js-2.
- The Back-end consisted of a MongoDB with an Express (RESTful Api) Server.
- The web application also allowed the 25 employees who were using it to geo-tag shipments for tracking and on time delivery.
- During development I, along with a QA Lead wrote tests to ascertain that the application performed according to requirements.
- Provided training to all the 25 Employees in the usage of the web application.

### QBS Polska Sp. Z.o.o

#### IT Specialist

Dec 2015 - Jun 2017, Warsaw, Poland

QBS Polska is a small distributor of quality sausage coverings.

- Developed a locally deployed web application that had an ability to store information related to sale and purchase of sausage coverings which resultantly allowed the organization to know its financial position.
- The development was test-driven by employing unit testing through Jest JavaScript Framework.
- The UI was designed by Figma, coded in PHP with MySQL database at it back-end.

#### NRDF

Dec 2013 - Dec 2014, Peshawar, Pakistan

#### Project Officer

National Research and Development Fund at the time was working on an education project which was funded by UNICEF and the duties assigned covered the following:

- Preparation and Sharing of all Project-related documents such as Workplan and Logical Framework with the Project Manager.
- Overlooking of all operational activities.

#### Azam Khan Enterprises

Jun 2011 - Aug 2012, Peshawar, Pakistan

#### Database Administrator

Azam Khan Enterprises deals in delivering shipment and supplies to clients in Afghanistan and Pakistan.

 Developed a MySQL database system for the organization to help it cope with all the data related to shipments for NATO forces operating in Afghanistan.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

9 9 9 ReactJS React-Chart-JS2 9 9 9 ReactLeafletJS 9 9 NodeJS 0 0 ExpressJS (RESTful) 0 0 Apache Servers phpmyadmin, 000 PgAdmin4 HTML5 CSS3 Jest 0 0 Spring MVC 0 0 **Spring Boot** 9 9 MongoDB 0 0 0 MySQL 0 0 0 Postgresql Django

## **OTHER SKILLS**

**ODK Collect** 

Project Management, Microsoft Office, Microsoft PowerBI, Figma, Report Writing, Presentation, Knowledge Management and Model Building

## **EDUCATION**

Masters in Business Computing University of Hertfordshire (2012-2013, Hatfield, UK)

B.S. in Business Information Systems

University of Hertfordshire Second Class Honors (2009-2011, Hatfield, UK)

Diploma in Business

Hertfordshire International College

(2008-2009, Hatfield, UK)

## REFERENCES

Available on request